No one comes close to James Bond, 007.
For Your Eyes Only is a adventure, action, thriller film directed by John Glen.
A British spy ship has sunk and on board was a hi-tech encryption device.
James Bond is sent to find the device that holds British launching
instructions before the enemy Soviets get to it first.
James Bond, played by Roger Moore.
Melina Havelock, played by Carole Bouquet.
Milos Columbo, played by Chaim Topol.
Aristotle Kristatos, played by Julian Glover.
Bibi Dahl, played by Lynn-Holly Johnson.
Countess Lisl von Schlaf, played by Cassandra Harris.
For Your Eyes Only is a 1981 spy film, the twelfth film in the James Bond franchise produced by Eon
Productions, and the fifth to star Roger Moore as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond.
The film also co-stars Carole Bouquet, Chaim Topol, Lynn-Holly Johnson and Julian Glover, and marked the feature directorial
debut of John Glen, who had served as a film editor and second unit director on previous films in the series.
The film was written by Richard Maibaum and Michael G.
Although the script is principally based on two Ian Fleming short stories, "For Your Eyes Only" and "Risico", some elements of
the plot were also inspired by the novels Live and Let Die, Goldfinger and On Her Majesty's Secret Service.
The film follows Bond as he attempts to locate a missile command system while becoming tangled in a web of deception spun
by rival Greek smugglers along with Melina Havelock, a woman seeking to avenge the murder of her parents.
After the science-fiction-focused Moonraker, the producers wanted a return to the
style of the early Bond films and the works of 007 creator Fleming.
For Your Eyes Only followed a grittier, more realistic approach and a narrative theme of
revenge and its consequences, rather than the fantasy narrative of Moonraker.
Filming took place from September 1980 to February 1981, and locations included Greece,
Italy and the United Kingdom, while underwater footage was shot in the Bahamas.
Sheena Easton performed the title theme song.
For Your Eyes Only was released in the UK on 24 June 1981 and in the US two
days later; it received a mixed-to-positive critical reception.
The film's reputation has improved over time, with reviewers praising the more
serious tone in comparison to previous entries in the series.
The film was a financial success, generating $195.3 million worldwide.
For Your Eyes Only was the final Bond film to be distributed solely by United Artists; the
company was absorbed by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer soon after this film's release.
It was followed by Octopussy in 1983.
The film explores themes of sea, assassin, london,
england, smuggling (contraband), submarine.
The tone is intense.